My name is Chris Goodswin. I'm a senior character artist working on Hunt Showdown, which will be an
early access game for PC. It's a competitive PvP where there's also PvE elements as well.
Marvel's designer enabled us to get a consistent look across all the hunters and the grunts. The
grunts, for instance, are an AI class. They're the living dead, if you like, that are walking around
the map. And obviously we want to make sure they look historically accurate. And also using Marvel's
designer to build up a quick and workable library of assets that we can reuse as a starting point or
reuse between, say, the grunts and the hunters. So if we create our shirt, we don't have to start
from the beginning again. We can actually take this across to the grunts and then rework it.
It also enabled us to do quick, rapid prototyping. So we could quickly create a garment and hand to
the concept team to give a quick iteration while we're exploring the actual direction for some of
the monsters. And that's what we're going to be doing. We're going to be working on the
monsters and creatures within the game. I often find the way to treat Marvel's design is to treat
it like a modeling piece of software. When creating the garments, we use a lot of freezing.
Say it would be a nice fold down the arm or maybe across the back of the character. You can then
freeze that element to make sure that's locked into place. Another aspect that I'd like to use
is to pin something. So once you've actually found a unique look of the fold, you quickly pin it into
place and you can come back to it at a later date. But it pretty much sets it in stone and then you
can work around the model. You can export the UVs. We've found this useful because we like to
texture the high resolution mesh. So then when we bake the information down to our in-game models,
if you have a nice stripe pattern, that would actually follow through the folds and enables
to give a much more realistic look to the actual characters. We brought animation into Marvelous
Designer in order for us to have those sort of unique folds, say within the creases of the arms
or the back of the knees or anywhere else that's needed on the character. Looking at our project,
looking at Hunter Showdown, it would be great if we could have a function to rip the actual garments.
I know it's very specific, but if you could literally grab it and rip it to give a much more
natural flow, say to a ripped shirt, it enables to get a much more quicker and much more natural look to that.